Guide to the Fred Eggan Papers 1870-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series IV: Theory and Method
  - Subseries 6: Development and Change
    - Research Center in Economic Development and Cultural Change, Faculty Seminar in Economic Development and Cultural Change, manuscripts, minutes, notes, 1951-1952 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Research Center in Economic Development and Cultural Change, "Human Aspects of Technical Change, " manuscript, 1951 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - U.S. Department of State, Office of Public Affairs, Point Four Program, government publications, 1951 (Box 49, Folder 13)
- Series V: World Ethnography
  This series has been divided into nine subseries; three of which contain further subdivisions. While Eggan's primary ethnographic interests focused on the Philippines and native North America, Eggan collected an extensive amount of material on other parts and peoples of the world. These secondary interests are represented in subseries on Africa, Asia, Australia and Oceania, Europe, Meso- and South America. The materials in these subseries are course syllabi, notes, and outlines, bibliographies, lecture and research notes, manuscripts and reprints, student papers, project proposals, and dissertations, correspondence, pamphlets, abstracts, and maps and charts. These materials range in date from 1913 to 1978, with the bulk of the series originating from the 1930s, 40s, and 50s.
  Subseries 5: Europe, contains Robert Pehrson Research Materials. Pehrson was a doctoral student under Eggan and received his Ph.D. in Anthropology from the University of Chicago. His dissertation concerned the social organization of the Lapps or Saami of northern Scandinavia. After Pehrson's death in 1955, many of his papers, especially his Lappish, northern European, and northern Asian materials, were transferred to Eggan.
  - Subseries 1: General
    - Anthro 230 a, b, c, Peoples of the World, syllabus, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Races of the Old World, Ralph Linton, notes, bibliography, undated (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - World Ethnography, lecture notes, 1933 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Spencer, Robert F., An Ethno-Atlas, manual, 1956 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 2: Africa
    - "A Comparison of the Bakitava and the Todas, " student paper, 1931 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Problems in African Anthropology, syllabus, 1941 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Balèga, notes, undated (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - [Gray], "Sonjo Kinship Terms, " manuscript, undated (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Sangree, Walter H., "Youths as Elders and Infants as Ancestors, " manuscript, ca.1973 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Symposium on Malagasy Kinship and Social Structure, manuscripts, reprint, correspondence, notes, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Trever, J. C., reprint, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - unidentified, "Ethnology of Africa, " notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Asia
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Anthro 230, Asia, syllabus, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Islam and the West, Robert Redfield and Milton Singer, outline, bibliography, manuscript, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Anthro 349, Peoples of Asia, Fay-Cooper Cole, notes, bibliography, map, 1939 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Peoples of Asia, Ralph Linton, notes, 1932 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Bacon, Elizabeth, "Culture Areas of Asia, " manuscript, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Institute of the Society for Social Research, population problems in the Far East, program, notes, 1945 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Southwest Asia
      - Syria, notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Barth, Fredrik, "Father's Brother's Daughter Marriage in Kurdistan, " manuscript, Robert Pehrson's notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Eberhard, Wolfram, reprint, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Fuller, Anne H., bibliography, manuscript, field notes, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Central and Northern Asia
      - Notes, maps, undated (Box 50, Folder 14-15)
      - Notes, on "Kazakh-Kirgis, " by Lawrence Krader, undated (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - Anthro 230a, Introduction to the Ethnology of Central Asia, syllabi, notes, 1946-1952 (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - Anthro 231, Peoples of Central and Northern Asia--Lawrence Krader, Fred Eggan, syllabi, bibliographies, handouts, notes, maps, 1956-1957, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 18-19)
      - Anthro 231, Peoples of Central and Northern Asia--Lawrence Krader, Fred Eggan, maps, 1956-1957,1960 (Box A)
      - Hattori, Takeshi, "Gilyak Kinship Terms, " translated by K. Kymn and V. Carroll, manuscript, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Krader, Lawrence, "Corporate Groups and the Organization of Inner Asian Society, " "Social Change in Outer Mongolia, " manuscripts, correspondence, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - LeVine, Robert A., "The Sociology of Siberian Shamanism, " M.A. thesis, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Murdock, George P., "A Proposal to Compile an Atlas and Outline of Eurasiatic Cultures, part I, " proposal, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Posch, Udo, "Outer-Mongolia Project, " proposal, ca.1960 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Robinson, Sarah A., "The Policies for Minority Nationalities of Russia and Their Application in Northern Asia, " student paper, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Shimkin, D. B., reprint, notes, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Tolstov, S. P., "Central Asian Scythians in the Light of the Latest Archaeological Discoveries, " manuscript, undated (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - miscellaneous, clippings, 1951 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - miscellaneous, reprints, 1948-1962 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Sub-subseries 4: South Asia
      - Notes, India, memorandum, ca.1931-1954 (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Notes, Nayar, undated (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - Maps, undated (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - Indian Village, Robert Redfield and Milton Singer, manuscripts, syllabus, reprint, 1954 (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - Anthro 438, Religion in South Asia, Nur Yalman and McKim Marriott, syllabus, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - Anthro 465, South and East Asia, Starr, reprint, manuscripts, correspondence, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 16)
      - Contemporary Problems in South and East Asia, seminar program, bibliography, 1951-1952 (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - Flying Carpet over India and Pakistan, faculty seminar, undated (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - Burling, [Robbins], "Semantic Components of Garo Kinship Terms, " manuscript, undated (Box 51, Folder 19)
      - Dargan, Marie E., "Ceremonies of Social Distance, " student paper, 1931 (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - Ghosh, Dipali, Kachari correspondence, 1965 (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - Griffin, Cleo C., "The Ethnology of India, " student paper, 1937 (Box 51, Folder 22)
      - Joseph, Phyllis, "Suttee, " student paper, 1931 (Box 51, Folder 23)
      - Problems and Materials, " syllabus, notes, undated (Box 51, Folder 24)
      - Opler, Morris and Rudra Datt Singh, reprint, notes, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 25)
      - Pehrson, Robert N., "Proposed Research in Baluchistan, " manuscript, correspondence, ca.1954-1955 (Box 51, Folder 26)
      - Pugh, [Frank], "Khasi Kinship Terms, " manuscript, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Smith, Marian W., reprint, 1946 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Unidentified, "Caste from an Anthropological Point of View, " manuscript, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Unidentified, "Economic Survey of the Village of Thettupalle, South India, " manuscript, undated (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Unidentified, "Kinship and Marriage Among the Khasi, " proposal, undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Unidentified, "The Kinship System of the Nayar of Malabar, " manuscript, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Sub-subseries 5: Southeast Asia
      - Notes, undated (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - Notes, on "Kinship in Southeast Asia, " by P. K. Benedict, ca.1941 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Borneo, reprints, map, notes, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Burma, notes, undated (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - Indonesia, notes, undated (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Indonesia, Manggarai, notes, undated (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - Malaysia, bibliographies, notes, undated (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - Malaysia, Anthro 333, 334, 356, 434, Peoples of Malaysia, syllabi, notes, maps, undated (Box 52, Folder 14-15)
      - Malaysia, Anthro 356, Malaysia, Fay-Cooper Cole, Eggan's student notebook, undated (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - Malaysia, Anthro 357, Peoples of the South Pacific, Fay-Cooper Cole, "Malaysia, " Eggan's student paper, 1932 (Box 52, Folder 17)
      - Malaysia, "Ethnography of Malaysia, " manuscript, notes, 1930 (Box 52, Folder 18)
      - Malaysia, "Outline, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 52, Folder 19)
      - Condominas, Georges, "Les Mnong Gar, " "The Mnong Gar of Viet Nam" translated by Mel Medwick, manuscripts, correspondence, 1958, 1964 (Box 52, Folder 20)
      - Daw Kin Kin U, "The Institution of Marriage in Burmese-Muslim Community, " manuscript, correspondence, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 21)
      - Kennedy, Raymond, "Marriage Class and Totemism in Eastern Indonesia, " manuscript, undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - [Leach, Edmund], "A Sociological Classification of the Peoples of Sarawak, " manuscript, undated (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Loeb, Edwin M., "Social Organization and the Long House in Southeast Asia and Micronesia, " manuscript, undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Southeast Asia Institute, Language Series, no. 1-4, pamphlets, undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - University of Michigan, Center for South and Southeast Asian Studies, International Conference on Borobudur, reprints, manuscripts, correspondence, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Yale University, Southeast Asia Studies, "Ethnic Groups of Northern Southeast Asia, " manuscript, notes, 1950, 1953, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Sub-subseries 6: East Asia
      - General, American Council of Learned Societies, "Far Eastern Leaflets, " pamphlet, 1942 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - General, Norton S. Ginsburg, "Geography of the Far East, " manuscript, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - General, Lauriston Ward, "An Introductory Bibliography of Far Eastern Archaeology, " manuscript, 1948 (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - China, notes, map, undated (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - China, Tibet, notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - China, review of The Chinese Kinship System by Han Yi Fêng, manuscript, notes, 1938 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - China, [J. W. Bennett], "Methods in the Study of Early Chinese Culture, " manuscript, undated (Box 53, Folder 13)
      - China, Francis L. K. Hsu, charts, undated (Box 53, Folder 14)
      - China, University of Chicago, "Program of Chinese Studies, "1949 (Box 53, Folder 15)
      - Japan, notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
      - Japan, Kyosuke Kindaichi, reprint, 1949 (Box 53, Folder 17)
      - Japan, Bertram Kraus, "Japanese Prehistoric Archaeology, " manuscript, undated (Box 53, Folder 18)
      - Japan, Scientific Film Series, "Ainu' River-Fishery, " pamphlet, 1953 (Box 53, Folder 19)
      - Japan, Stanford University, Civil Affairs Training School, "The History of Japan, " manuscript, undated (Box 53, Folder 20)
      - A Guide to Japanese Reference and Research Materials, "1954 (Box 53, Folder 21)
      - Japan, University of Michigan, Civil Affairs Training School, lecture outlines, 1944 (Box 53, Folder 22)
      - Korea, American Geographical Society, "Korean Backdrop, " pamphlet, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 23)
      - Korea, G. W. Hewes, C. H. Kim, and H. Oh, "Korean Kinship Terms, " handout, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 24)
  - Subseries 4: Australia and Oceania
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 25)
      - Notes, archaeology, undated (Box 53, Folder 26)
      - Notes, map, clipping, 1937 (Box 53, Folder 27)
      - Anthro 210, 230 B, 231, Micronesia, Polynesia, and Melanesia, syllabi, manuscripts, 1947-1948 (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Anthro 357, Peoples of the South Pacific, Fay-Cooper Cole, notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Review of Island Peoples of the Western Pacific, Micronesia and Melanesia by Herbert W. Krieger, clipping, ca.1945 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Keesing, Felix, reprint, notes, 1950 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Linton, Ralph, manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Australia
      - Notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - "The Culture of Australia, " "Notes on Australia, " manuscripts, undated (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Birdsell, Joseph B., "New Data on Racial Stratification in Australasia, " abstracts, undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Bott, Elizabeth, "Local Organization and Social Structure in Australia, " manuscript, undated (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - Davidson, David S., "A Preliminary Register of Australian Tribes and Hordes, " manuscript, 1938 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Radcliffe-Brown, A. R., reprint, 1930 (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - Tax, Sol, "Paper on Australia, " manuscript, undated (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Melanesia
      - Notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 13-14)
      - Iatmul, notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 15)
      - New Hebrides, notes, maps, undated (Box 54, Folder 16)
      - Brandwie, Ernest, "Kinship Structure and Social Organization of the Mbowamb, West Central Highlands of New Guinea, " student paper, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 17)
      - Fathauer, George H., "Kinship and Social Structure of the Trobriand Islanders, " manuscript, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 18)
      - Foege, H., "Notes on Melanesia, " manuscript, undated (Box 54, Folder 19)
      - Foster, Robert, reprint, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 20)
      - Garlick, Catherine, "Malinowski's Argonauts of the Western Pacific, " student paper, undated (Box 54, Folder 21)
      - Hartman, Ellen, "Melanesia, " "Social Organization of the New Hebrides, New Caledonia, and Fiji Islands, " student papers, 1928 (Box 54, Folder 22)
      - Le Roux, C. C. F. M., De Bergpapoea's van Nieuw-Guinea en hun Woongebied, publisher's synopsis, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 23)
      - Rawlins, Mrs., and R. M. Zingg, "Melanesia, " chart, undated (Box 54, Folder 24)
      - Setzler, J. M., "Melanesian Islands, " student paper, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Wheatcroft, Wilson, "The Legacy of Afekan, " abstract, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Unidentified, "Melanesia, " manuscripts, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Unidentified, review of The History of Melanesian Society by W. H. R. Rivers, manuscript, undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Unidentified, "The Banaro Society, " manuscript, undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Unidentified, "Black Spots, " "Stone Age Frontier, " clippings, 1945 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Sub-subseries 4: Micronesia
      - "Micronesia, " manuscript, outline, bibliography, charts, notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Jacobs, Alan H., "The Kinship System and Land Resources on Truk, " "We, the Tikopia, " student papers, bibliography, 1952 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Schneider, David M., "The Social Organization of Yap, " manuscript, undated (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - Spoehr, Alexander, reprints, notes, 1949, 1951 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Sub-subseries 5: Polynesia
      - Notes, manuscripts, bibliography, undated (Box 55, Folder 11-12)
      - Maori, notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 13)
      - Tonga, notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 14)
      - Fathauer, George H., "The Culture of the Marquesas Islands, " student paper, 1940 (Box 55, Folder 15)
      - Firth, Raymond, "History and Traditions of Tikopia, " manuscript, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 16)
      - Goldman, Irving, reprint, notes, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 17)
      - Ostlund, Ruth V., "Report on Linton's Ethnology of Polynesia and Micronesia, " student paper, 1935 (Box 55, Folder 18)
      - Unidentified, "American Indians in the Pacific, " contents, 1952 (Box 55, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 5: Europe
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 20)
      - Mediterranean kin terms, handout, undated (Box 55, Folder 21)
      - Foreword to Milocca by Charlotte G. Chapman, manuscript, correspondence, 1970-1978 (Box 55, Folder 22)
      - Howell, F. Clark, reprint, 1952 (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Saami (Lapps)--Robert Pehrson Research Materials
      - Notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
      - Bibliographies, undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Godparenthood, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, clipping, 1952 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Kin charts, undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Linguistics, notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Nomad school, manuscripts, undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Personality, manuscripts, program, notes, n.d (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Reindeer herding, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1949-1953 (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - Religion, reprint, memoranda, correspondence, notes, 1953 (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - Socialization, manuscript, correspondence, 1953 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - Synopsis of Medelby by Martin Allwood and Inga-Britt Ranemark, manuscript, undated (Box 56, Folder 12)
      - "The Bilateral Network of Social Relations in Könkämä Lapp District, " manuscript, correspondence, notes, maps1954 (Box 56, Folder 13-15)
      - "Decision Making Among the Könkämä Lapps, " manuscripts, notes, 1951 (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
      - "Inventory of Field Material, Sirkas Lapp Group, " manuscript, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - "The Reindeer-Breeding Peoples, " "En Amerikan pa Renskillning, " manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1949-1954 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - "Naming among the Karesuando Lapps, " with Ian Whitaker, manuscript, correspondence, notes, 1952 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - Congrès International des Sciences Anthropologiques et Ethnologiques, abstracts, 1952 (Box 57, Folder 6)
      - Erixon, Sigurd, manuscripts, synopsis, 1951 (Box 57, Folder 7)
      - Lapska Traditioner, pamphlets, undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
      - Whitaker, Ian, correspondence, notes, 1952-53 (Box 57, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous, clippings, 1952,1954 (Box B)
      - Miscellaneous, clippings, 1952, 1954 (Box 57, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous, reprints, 1913-1952 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 6: North America
    - French Canada, notes, undated (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - "The Anthropological Approach to the Study of American Civilization, " Conference on Studies in American Civilization, manuscripts, 1954 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Lynd, Robert S. and Helen M., Middletown, Robert Pehrson's excerpts, n.d (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Spencer, Robert F., "A School is to Learn, " manuscript, undated (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Warner, W. Lloyd "Structure of American Life, " Robert Perhson's excerpts, undated (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, reprints, 1951-1952 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 7: Mesoamerica
    - General, notes, map, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - General, Anthro 230, Program on Middle America, Sol Tax, manuscripts, outline, syllabus, maps, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - General, Anthro 353, Maya, Aztec, and Related Cultures, Robert Redfield, notes, syllabi, charts, maps, 1932 (Box 58, Folder 3-4)
    - General, Anthro 353, Anthro 354, Present Day Mexico, Robert Redfield, bibliographies, notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Aztec, notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Chontal, notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Huichol, notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Sierra Popoluca, notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Bennett, W. W., "Kinship, " Tarahumara, partial manuscript, undated (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Carrasco, Pedro, "The Social Organization of Ancient Mexico, " manuscript, correspondence, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Diebold, A. Richard, Jr., "The Reflection of Coresidence in Mareño Kinship Terminology, " manuscript, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Leonard, Juan, Lacandones correspondence, enclosures, 1955 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Redfield, Robert, Maya, memorandum, outline, 1942 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Starr, Betty, "Los Tuxtlas, " abstract, 1950 (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Thompson, Eric, Maya, correspondence, notes, 1932 (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Villa Rojas, Alfonso, "Notas etnograficas sobre los Indios Tzotziles y Tzeltales del estado Chiapas, Mexico, " "Notas sobre el sistema familiar de los Indios Tzeltales de Chiapas, Mexico, " student papers, 1939 (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 8: South America
    - General, bibliographies, notes, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 18-20)
    - General, population and language, notes, charts, maps, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - General, "Notes of Course on South America by Leslie Spier, " manuscript, charts, maps, notes, 1930 (Box 59, Folder 2-3)
    - General, South America, course outline, undated (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Amazon, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Andes, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Circum-Carribean Area, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Tierra del Fuego, notes, clipping, 1948 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Apinayé, Ramkókamekra, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Araucani, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Boro, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Gê, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Maué, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Siriono, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Tupi, undated (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Tupinamba, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Collier, Donald, Foreword to Travels and Archaeology in South Chile, by Junius B. Bird, manuscript, ca.1988 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Goldman, Irving, "Phratry, Gens, and Kinship among the Cubéo Indians of the Vaupes, Colombia, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Greenberg, Joseph, "Tentative Linguistic Classification of Cenral and South America, " manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1957 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Holloman, Regina, San Blas Cuna, correspondence, enclosures, 1967 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Keller, Gordon, "A Study of Social Organization in South America, " student paper, 1948 (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - McAllister, J. G., "Notes on the Culture of the Amazon, " manuscript, 1931 (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - Murphy, Robert F., "Matrilocality and Patrilineality in Mundurucú Society, " manuscript, correspondence, 1954 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Starr, Betty, notes on "Le Civilization Guayano-Amazonienne et ses provinces culturelle" by Alfred Metraux, manuscript, ca.1946 (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - University of California, South America, course outline, undated (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - W. W. Over Museum, Museum News, "The Lagos Santa Project, " newsletter, 1956 (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous, reprints, 1935-1951 (Box 59, Folder 27)
  - Subseries 9: Maps and Charts
    - General, Robert J. Braidwood, W.M. Krogman, and Sol Tax, "Time, Space, and Man," map, 1946 (Box A)
    - Africa, A.K. Lobeck, "Physiographic Diagram of Africa," pamphlet, 1946 (Box B)
    - Asia, "Dominant Economies," map, undated (Box B)
    - Asia, "Kingship Terms: Central Asia," chart, after Lawrence Krader, undated (Box B)
    - Asia, A.K. Lobeck, "Physiographic Diagram of Asia," pamphlets, 1945 (Box B)
    - Australia and Oceania, maps, undated (Box A)
    - Australia and Oceania, "Polynesia: Comparative Table for Material Culture," charts, undated (Box B)
    - Europe, A.K. Lobeck, "Physiographic Diagram of Europe," pamphlet, 1947 (Box B)
- Series VI: North American Indian Files
  This series consists of field notes, reading notes, lecture notes, bibliographies, manuscripts, student papers, research proposals, reprints, abstracts, reviews, pamphlets, media clippings, correspondence, and maps and charts. The materials date from 1922-1990 and have been divided by geographical region into 15 subseries.